

Kelly Ann McNamara

Designer & Developer Provisional RGD kellyannmcnamara.ca hi@kellyannmcnamara.ca

Cover Letter

Hello Meredith, (as well as John and Micheal)

I would start by thanking you for speaking at Humber the other day and completely captivating my interest about the opportunities that Critical Mass offers interns.

Prior to enrolling into the Humber Web Development program I was Digital Designer who graduated in 2014 from Cambrian College Advanced Graphic Design diploma program. Graduating with honors and the RDG Student Award of Excellence, I entered field as a graphic designer at a start up marketing company. Working within a start-up allowed me to gain valuable skills that may of been tasked to other people in a larger firm, showing me a deeper appropriation for those roles, and a respect for those who do them. There, I was consistently learning, mainly focusing on user experience and interaction with online brands, structure and digital design.

As a creature of intense curiosity, I never just want to work on a project but immerse myself in all of the playing factors. My curiosity has not only shown great advantages within design but also pushed me to become a web developer as well. Consistently wanting to out do what has been created before, the thirst for improvement and knowledge doesn't seem to ever quite be satisfied.

Prior to continuing, I would like to thank you for taking the time to review my resume. I look forward to meeting with you to discuss future opportunities.



Kelly Ann McNamara

Designer & Developer Provisional RGD kellyannmcnamara.ca hi@kellyannmcnamara.ca

Development Skills

HTML5 CSS3

JavaScript JQuery

MySQL PHP XML ASP.NET PL/SQL

Accessibility

Analytic Tracking & Research

Data Flow

Git MCV Oracle PhpStorm Project Management
Site Architecture
SEO & SEM Auditing
SEO & SEM Implication

Visual Studio Web Optimization Website Management

XAMP

Design Skills

Web Design
UX/UI Design

Cross Platform Design Developing Cross Platform

Interactive Design Adobe Suites Design Strategy Branding Wordpress Marketing Strategies

Research Competitors

Photography

Food Staging
Hand Illustration
Typography
Microsoft Office

Freelance Clients

81 Entertainment

Alex Brott – Sage Real Estate Ltd.

Apartmate Erika Donavan – Web Developer

IV Lounge

J&F Equipment Sales

Loanerr

ThePalam Inc.

The Septmeber

Education

Humber College Web Development (Post–Grad) 2016 – Present

Cambrian College Graphic Design (PAGD) 2011 – 2014

Honors & Awards

RGD Student Award The Award of Excellence April 2014

Cambrian College Dean List April 2014

Online Profiles

be.net/kellyannmcnamara codepen.io/kellyannmcnamara/ github.com/kellyannmcnamara01 blog.kellyannmcnamara.ca LinkedIn Kelly Ann McNamara



Kelly Ann McNamara

Designer & Developer Provisional RGD kellyannmcnamara.ca hi@kellyannmcnamara.ca

Experience

Orchestra Marketing

Digital & UX/UI Designer August 2014 – June 2016

Starting as an intern at the end of August 2014 I was brought on as full-time team member as the Junior Designer in January 2015. My role quickly developed and was I promoted to Intermediate Designer by April 2015. My role in this start-up was consistently changing between user experience and interaction, social media marketing and web design. Shortly after this fast past learning experience I was promoted to Digital Designer as the team's lead web designer and the UX/UI specialist. This is where my desire to learn more web development fostered and grew until I enrolled into the post graduate program at Humber College.

kellyannmcnamara.ca

Digital & UX/UX Designer, Project Manager and Web Developer June 2011 – Present

Consistently working on freelance projects has allowed an endless flow of learning many different roles independently. It's important to be challenged regularly and working directly with clients has taught many priceless lessons. Here is where the drive for management, relationship building and organization lives strong and strives.

BitterSweet Sudbury

Designer, Developer & Event Coordinator January 2014 – April 2014

An interactive community project coordinated by the graduating class of the PAGD program, highlighting the sliver linings of Sudbury. We were split into teams and functioned liked a full service agency. The team I was placed on ended up being chosen as the lead designers and web developers for the over all project. Coding and designing my first live site.

Grip Limited

Design Intern
November 2013 – December 2013

Finding your own 8 week co-op placement was part of the PAGD program. This was also my first interview with a large company, and it was over Skype. This opportunity allowed me to immerse myself in a full service agency and their many different teams. Working with clients and organizing in-house projects was an over all incredible experience.

RickSticks

Design Intern November 2011 – May 2012

This intimate and friendly agency was my first experience working as a designer and with web developers. It was an alerting full-day high school co-op that took place over my entire grade 12 year.